<books>
    <book ID="HDBrownie_Sundirge_Story" Title="Sole Survivors">
        <page>
The robed figure shifts in her seat, her demeanor betraying little sign of disquiet. "When you're a smuggler, the most important question at all times is 'Which way is down?'.

"When down is nowhere, when you're swimmin' in the great vast, you're happy as a comet. The wind at your back, the crew and cargo safe. There are no authorities there, not even the Coven, who can take that from you.

"When down is earth, it depends. Are you leavin' or arrivin'? Is it a trade hub or just some hunk o' dirt? Most worlds ain't worth landin' on, but some are.

"But when down is a void blacker than the space between rocks..."

She pauses, although I'm unsure if she's collecting herself or if it's for effect. "{{Y|*Then*}}... there's some worry worth worryin'. The final authority, the one {{Y|*no*}} man can run from, is the nature of the universe."

I catch a brief glimpse of her eyes despite the shroud, and am left with a brief impression of one iris and one lens staring directly into my own. Somehow, even the cold metal is haunted.
</page><page>
"But you... survived," I offer, stating the obvious.

She shrugs. "What's the point? A captain ain't no thing without her ship. Without her crew. Why did the void spit out its food? Why was it only us what got out?"

I tilt my head. "Us?"

She gestures with her head at the [TODO: what does it look like] behind her whose presence I only just registered. I don't know how I know, but I realize its attention has been on me this whole time.

"Who is... this?"

"You think I {{Y|*name*}} every bit o' the ship? It's our mast. Well, just {{Y|*my*}} mast now."

The [TODO] signals its assent without a single thing about it moving. Just what kind of being is this?

"An' speakin' of, that's why I asked you here today."
</page><page>
She takes in a deep breath and sighs. "I've been livin' on borrowed time for the last ten years. Even with my... modifications, my organs're just about done. Some miracle work that doctor did, no doubt, but I gotta go sooner or later."

I blink in surprise. "You want me to..." I glance at the [TODO]. "What, take ownership of the mast?"

She shakes her head. "Not ownership. Companionship. Let it know there's good in this world. Somethin' I never could do."

I pause, thinking about it for a moment, but I already decided the moment she asked.

"I'll do it."

She nods. "Knew y'would. You've got a good heart, kid. Now take your new pal and go. I'm tireder than a man what swam the space between stars."

I stand up, gently cradle the mast in my arms, and turn to leave, but I feel a tug on my sleeve. "One more thing, young'n."
</page><page>
I meet her gaze again, this time clearly seeing how very much of her countenance is machine.

"Never pray on a star. The wrong one might answer."            
        </page>
    </book>
</books>
